Harry Watson

Rochford, Essex
Harrydwatson@outlook.com

07944 861755

Hello,

I'm Harry, an enthusiastic individual with a passion for learning and a drive to excel in any field I enter. While I may be at the beginning of my professional journey, my eagerness to grow and adapt is boundless.

I've engaged in various projects and experiences, from construction and engineering, coaching in a workout environment and managing a small startup café. Where I've cultivated skills such as problem solving, time management, communication, and practical skills.

I thrive in laid-back, collaborative work environments where creativity flourishes. I'm all about maintaining a healthy work-life balance and believe in the power of a relaxed atmosphere to fuel productivity and innovation.

Employment History

Dellow Group

Trainee Engineer - August 2023 - Present

- Learning basic electrical engineering in relation to alarm systems.
- Finding and correcting faults in a variety of different alarm and CCTV systems.
- Communicating with customers in a professional manner.
- Keeping my work vehicle clean and organised, ensuring that it has all the correct stock.
- Driving a work van to homes all over Essex.
- Installing new modern alarm systems and CCTV systems in accordance with the most up to date standards.
- Working at heights.
- Testing and servicing burglar alarm, CCTV and Fire alarm systems.
- Being on 24/7 emergency call out.
- Programming alarm and CCTV systems to accommodate for customers' requirements.
- Time managing my daily tasks to ensure I complete all my jobs for the day.
- Making important decisions to ensure the best outcome for both the customer and the business.

Katy's Café Lounge

Manager - February 2023 - August 2023

- Day to day running of the café, serving customers, cleaning, maintenance.
- Helping to organise events and plan to prepare for bookings.
- Handling upset customers in a professional manner that benefits the business and the customer equally.
- Creating recipes and new methods of preparing meals with very limited facilities.
- Cleaning and care of kitchen and bar appliances.
- Creating systems and spreadsheets to help organise the stock and maintenance of the café.
- Working alongside other departments to create marketing promotions.
- Creating social media posts to help market the business.
- Cashing out and creating daily reports.
- Overseeing the company email to communicate with external suppliers and clients.
- Training staff to work the bar and kitchen.
- Ensuring stock levels are kept up to date by processing stock deliveries and using the EPOS system to keep track of stock levels within the café.
- Creating Staff Rotas and working with a payroll team to ensure all staff are paid for their worked hours.
- Looking after staff members, ensuring they get a break during the day and helping them solve problems.
- Labelling food containers and writing out daily health and safety documents.
- Generating new ideas for the business such as menu design, systems, recipes and décor within the workplace and marketing promotions.
- Using the EPOS system to generate accurate profit margins and organising the till system to speed up the cashier process.

Katy's Café Lounge

Supervisor - August 2022 - February 2023

- Day to day running of the café, serving customers, cleaning, maintenance.
- Helping to organise events and plan to prepare for bookings.
- Handling upset customers in a professional manner that benefits the business and the customer equally.
- Using a coffee machine and creating latte art.
- Cooking and preparing basic meals such as breakfasts, paninis, sandwiches, and jacket potatoes.
- Cleaning and care of kitchen and bar appliances.
- Creating systems and spreadsheets to help organise the stock and maintenance of the café.
- Working alongside other departments to create marketing promotions.
- Making cocktails.
- Creating social media posts to help market the café.
- Cashing out and creating daily reports.
- Opening the café and getting it ready for service.
- Closing and locking.
- Consulted with customers to help them organise events within the café.
- Booking receipts into Xero.

L.A SADLER Carpentry

Entry Level - Jan 2021 - Jan 2022

- Collaborating alongside my mentor, solving problems, organising construction projects, communicating with clients, and cooperating with other firms.
- Using specialist tools to fit furniture, manipulate wood and remove old material.
- General cleaning of building sites and looking after tools.
- Hauling heavy objects.

CrossFit Muscle Yard

Apprenticeship (Level 3 Personal Training) - September 2019 - Jan 2021

- Assisting coaches with classes. Motivating clients, helping clients with exercise technique, giving advice, and making sure clients are safe.
- General cleaning of the gym, bathrooms, hoovering and moping the floors, wiping equipment.
- Maintenance of gym equipment and occasionally partaking in construction projects within the gym.
- Managing the accounts software Putting receipts into QuickBooks.
- Managing merchandise Creating and utilizing systems on Excel, stock checking and stock rotation.
- Creating ads for Instagram and Facebook for the gym.
- Filming short clips for social media.
- Training clients 1-2-1.
- Creating workouts for clients.

A.J Chambers Recruitment

Voluntary Work Experience – March 2019 – March 2019

- Researching potential candidates for suitable positions finance and legal positions using Linkedln.
- Completing a backdoor project in which I investigated previous candidates during interview processes that had been placed without our knowledge. Clients do this to avoid recruitment fees.
- Working with specialized consultants to scout out potential candidates for them to contact.
- Using their CRM system (Arithon) to keep track of candidates and client data.

Education

South Essex College

Second Year (Level 2 Gym Instructing) - Sep 2018 - June 2019

Awarded Distinction*

South Essex College

First Year (Information Technology) - Sep 2017 - July 2018

- Awarded Distinction* Distinction*
- This course involved: Coding, computer systems, information systems, software design, e-commerce, computer networks, systems analysis and design, database design and website production.

Frogmore Community College

GCSE - Sep 2015 - June 2

- English Language and Literature 4
- Mathematics 4
- Photography C
- Geography B
- Science B
- Computer Science B
- Additional Science D
- Product Design C

Strengths & Skills

- Motivated
- Self-disciplined
- Curious
- Analytical
- Caring
- Honest
- Organized
- Team-oriented
- Problem Solving

- Bookkeeping
- Motivating others
- Training others
- Basic Excel
- Basic QuickBooks
- Computer systems
- Planning
- Open-minded/Want to learn
- Empathetic

- Communication
- Stock management
- EPOS System management
 - & implementation
- Kitchen Trained
- Bar Trained
- Barista Trained
- Stock management

Hobbies

- Cooking: Love getting creative in the kitchen, trying out new recipes, and making delicious meals for friends and family. Enjoy hosting foodie get-togethers, where we cook, chat, and bond over good food.
- Hanging out with friends: Enjoy spending leisure time socializing and participating in group activities, fostering teamwork, communication, and collaboration skills.
- Working Out: Passionate about fitness and maintaining a healthy lifestyle. Enjoy activities such as weightlifting, running, or yoga to stay active and energized.
- Spending Time with Family: Cherish moments with loved ones, engaging in activities like family dinners, outings, and game nights.
- Photography: Enthusiastic about capturing moments and telling stories through the lens. Proficient in
 using cameras, my personal favourite being a Polaroid, and photo editing software to produce high-quality
 images. I love the idea of capturing an image as authentically as possible as I believe that life is very much an
 'in the moment' thing.

References

I can provide reference details if required, but for confidentiality reasons, I will not be providing them in this document.